Listen to a talk in a psychology class.
Today we're going to talk about shyness and discuss recent research on ways to
help children learn to interact socially.
Many people consider themselves shy.
In fact, forty percent of people who took part in our survey said they
were shy--- that's two out of every five people.
And there are studies to indicate that the tendency toward shyness may be inherited.
But just because certain children are timid doesn't mean they are doomed to be shy forever.
There are things parents, teachers,
and the children themselves can do to overcome this tendency---
and even to prevent it.
One researcher found that if parents gently push their shy children to try new
things, they can help these children become less afraid and less inhibited.
Another way to help shy children is to train them in social skills.
For example, there are special training groups where children are taught things like looking
at other children while talking to them, talking about other people's interests, and even smiling.
These groups have been very successful at giving shy children a place to feel safe
and accepted,
and at building up their self-esteem.